nichegamer.com 2019-12-11

# Privacy Policy - Niche Gamer

**What kind of information do we collect?**

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our users. We only collect personal information from you when you enter a contest, respond to a survey, fill out a form or place comments on our site. When you submit any personal information, try to think twice before leaving comments or participating in online activities.

In this policy, “we”, “us” and “our” refer to (Niche Gamer). For more information about us, see our [about page](https://nichegamer.com/about/).

When you log in to leave comments on our site, you may be asked for the following information:

  * Your name
  * Your e-mail address
  * Your Facebook login
  * Your Twitter login

Niche Gamer does not collect or process any of this information. Our comments are handled through Disqus, a third party commenting program, which processes this information. You should abide by the terms of service and privacy policies from these third parties. You can browse Niche Gamer anonymously, in which none of your information is required.

We may process your account data (“ **account data** “). The account data may include your name and email address. The source of the account data is directly from the consumer but only with your explicit permission. The account data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

We may process information that you post for publication on our website or through our services (“ **publication data** “). The publication data may be processed for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

We may process your information included in your personal profile on our website (“ **profile data** “). The profile data may include your name, email address, profile pictures, date of birth, interests and hobbies. The profile data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business.

 **What is your information used for?**

Any information collected or submitted by you may be used in one or more of the following ways:

The processing of contest prizes and other giveaways, providing a personalized browsing experience, or receiving our RSS feed.

Your information, whether it’s public or kept private, will never be sold, exchanged, transferred, or handed over to any other company, without your consent. Niche Gamer is not held responsible for any personal information submitted to our partners.

 **How do we protect your information?**

We use quite a few security measures to protect your personal information once it’s submitted. Rest assured, it’s our business to keep your personal information safe.

 **International transfers of your personal data**

In this section, we provide information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

The hosting facilities for our website are situated in US, Europe and UK. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.

Mailing databases are situated in US and Australia. The European Commission has made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate safeguards, namely  EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield.

You acknowledge that personal data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or misuse) of such personal data by others.

 **Retaining and deleting personal data**

This section sets out our data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion of personal data.

Personal data that we process for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes.

We will retain and delete your personal data as follows:

  * Profile data containing personal data will be retained for duration of user subscription via Patreon.
  * Cookie data will be retained for no longer than 30 days.

Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, we may retain your personal data where such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

 **Your rights**

In this section, we have summarized the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.

Your principal rights under data protection law are:

  * the right to access;
  * the right to rectification;
  * the right to erasure;  

  * the right to restrict processing;  

  * the right to object to processing;  

  * the right to data portability;  

  * the right to complain to a supervisory authority  

  * the right to withdraw consent.

You have the right to confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. Provision of such information will be subject to:

  * the supply of appropriate evidence of your identity (for this purpose, we will usually accept a photocopy of your passport certified by a solicitor or bank plus an original copy of a utility bill showing your current address).

You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.

In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.

If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.

To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.

You may exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal data by contacting us using the details outlined in section 13.

 **Cookie use**

We use cookies on our website to save your submitted information, your preferences, and to gather data about our site traffic, so that we know how to better your experience at Niche Gamer.

The advertisements you see on our website are from third parties, which use information from your browsing history, and how you reached Niche Gamer, in order to serve ads that correlate to your interests. If you would like to learn more about how these ads work, and to know your options of not having your information used by these third parties, go [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

 **Cookies that we use**

We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * authentication – we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website;
  * security – we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally; 
  * advertising – we use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you (cookies used for this purpose are: Google AdSense, Google AdExchange, Avocet, PulsePoint, Teads, Skimlinks, Monetizer 101);
  * analysis – we use cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services (cookies used for this purpose are: Google Analytics, ComScore, Google Tag Manager, Crazy Egg, Facebook Audience, Google Analytics Audience); 
  * cookie consent – we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally. 

**Cookies used by our service providers**

Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.

We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is available at: [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

We publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by Google to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, Google will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the web using cookies. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: https://adssettings.google.com. You can also opt out of the AdSense partner network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: http://optout.networkadvertising.org. However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you may wish to consider using the Google browser plug-ins available at: https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996.

We use Avocet, OpenX, PulsePoint, Sovrn and Google Audiences to carry out retargeting and Header Bidding. These service uses cookies for retargeting ads and targeting ads based on your interests. You can view the privacy policy of these service providers at [http://avocet.io/privacy-policy](http://avocet.io/privacy-policy), [https://www.openx.com/legal/privacy-policy/](https://www.openx.com/legal/privacy-policy/), [https://www.pulsepoint.com/privacy-policy.html](https://www.pulsepoint.com/privacy-policy.html), [https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/) and [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

 **Cookie management**

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

  * https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome)
  * https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox)
  * http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera)
  * https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer)
  * https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari)
  * https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge)

Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites. If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.

 **Do we submit any of your information to outside parties?**

We do not sell, trade, or transfer any of your personal information to outside parties. The only exception to this rule is if said information is required to enforce applicable laws, site policies, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Niche Gamer and its staff.

 **Links to Third Party Websites**

The websites that we link to have their own privacy policies and terms of service agreements. Therefore, we have no responsibility or liability regarding links to external third parties and their content.

 **Amendments**

We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy. We may notify you of changes to this policy by email or through the private messaging system on our website.

By using our website, you are consenting to our privacy policy. This policy only applies to the information collected from our website. Any changes made to this policy will be shown here, and made note of by the last modified date, seen below.

We use a third-party provider, Venatus, to deliver targeted advertising and marketing to you. For information on how Venatus uses your data, please see Venatus’ privacy policy [here](https://www.venatusmedia.com/privacy/).

 _This policy was last modified on June 6th, 2019._
